<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <author>
    <name>DHH</name>
  </author>
  <id>tag:world.hey.com,2005:/dhh/feed</id>
  <link href="https://world.hey.com/dhh"/>
  <subtitle>Articles filtered from David Heinemeier Hansson without the uninterrogated privilege.</subtitle>
  <title>DHH but just the tech</title>
  <updated>2025-08-06T22:56:52+00:00</updated>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>David Heinemeier Hansson</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:world.hey.com,2005:World::Post/44314</id>
    <link href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/omarchy-is-on-the-move-8f848fa4"/>
    <published>2025-08-05T16:49:25Z</published>
    <summary>&lt;div class=&quot;trix-content&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://omarchy.org/&quot;&gt;Omarchy&lt;/a&gt; has been improving at a furious pace. Since it was &lt;a href=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/omarchy-is-out-4666dd31&quot;&gt;first released on June 26&lt;/a&gt;, I&#39;ve pushed out &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/basecamp/omarchy/releases&quot;&gt;18(!) new releases&lt;/a&gt; together with a rapidly growing community of collaborators, users, and new-to-Linux enthusiasts. We have about 3,500 early adopters on &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/tXFUdasqhY&quot;&gt;the Omarchy Discord&lt;/a&gt;, 250 pull requests processed, and one heck of an awesome &lt;a href=&quot;https://archlinux.org/&quot;&gt;Arch&lt;/a&gt; + &lt;a href=&quot;https://hypr.land/&quot;&gt;Hyprland&lt;/a&gt; Linux environment to show for it!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The latest release is 1.11.0, and it brings &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Cft6mZDzIng&quot;&gt;an entirely overhauled control menu&lt;/a&gt; to the experience. Now everything is controlled through a single, unified system that makes it super fast to operate Omarchy&#39;s settings and options through the keyboard. It&#39;s exactly the kind of hands-off-the-mouse operation that I&#39;ve always wanted, and with Linux, I&#39;ve been able to build it just to my tastes. It&#39;s a delight.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;There&#39;s really something special going on in Linux at the moment. Arch has been around for twenty years, but with Hyprland on top, it&#39;s been catapulted in front of an entirely new audience. Folks who&#39;d never thought that open source could be able to deliver a desktop experience &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/search?q=omarchy&amp;amp;src=typed_query&quot;&gt;worth giving up Windows or macOS for&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;Of course, Linux isn&#39;t for everyone. It&#39;s still an adventure! An awesome, teach-you-about-computers adventure, but not everyone is into computer adventures. Plenty of people are content with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3S5BLs51yDQ&amp;amp;t=52s&quot;&gt;a computer appliance&lt;/a&gt; where they never have to look under the hood. All good. Microsoft and Apple have those people covered.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;But the world is a big place! And in that big place, there are a growing number of computer enthusiasts who&#39;ve grown very disillusioned with both Microsoft and Apple. Folks who could be enticed to give Linux a look, if the barrier was a little lower and the benefits a little clearer. Those are the folks I&#39;m building Omarchy for.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary>
    <title>Omarchy is on the move</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T16:49:35Z</updated>
    <dc:date>2025-08-05T16:49:35Z</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>David Heinemeier Hansson</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:world.hey.com,2005:World::Post/44094</id>
    <link href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/it-s-a-beelink-baby-243fdaf1"/>
    <published>2025-07-23T18:03:06Z</published>
    <summary>&lt;div class=&quot;trix-content&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;It&#39;s only been two months since I discovered &lt;a href=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/cheap-mini-pcs-have-gotten-really-good-c70ab40f&quot;&gt;the power and joy of this new generation of mini PCs&lt;/a&gt;. My journey started out with a Minisforum UM870, which is a lovely machine, but since then, I&#39;ve come to really appreciate the work of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bee-link.com/&quot;&gt;Beelink&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gmktec.com/&quot;&gt;crowded&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.minisforum.com/&quot;&gt;market&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geekompc.com/&quot;&gt;for&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.asus.com/us/displays-desktops/nucs/all-series/&quot;&gt;mini&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://us-store.msi.com/cubi-series&quot;&gt;PCs&lt;/a&gt;, Beelink stands out with their superior build quality, their class-leading cooling and silent operation, and their use of fully Linux-compatible components (the UM870 shipped with a MediaTek bluetooth/wifi card that doesn&#39;t work with Linux!). It&#39;s the complete package at three super compelling price points.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;For $289, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bee-link.com/products/beelink-eqr5?variant=46994723242226&quot;&gt;you can get the EQR5&lt;/a&gt;, which runs an 8-core AMD Zen3 5825U that puts out 1723/6419 in Geekbench, and comes with 16GB RAM and 500GB NVMe. I&#39;ve run &lt;a href=&quot;https://omarchy.org/&quot;&gt;Omarchy&lt;/a&gt; on it, and it flies. For me, the main drawback was the lack of a DisplayPort, which kept me from using it with an Apple display, and the fact that the SER8 exists. But if you&#39;re on a budget, and you&#39;re fine with HDMI only, it&#39;s a wild bargain.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;For $499, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bee-link.com/products/beelink-ser8-8745hs?variant=46991244722418&quot;&gt;you can get the SER8&lt;/a&gt;. That&#39;s the price-to-performance sweet spot in the range. It uses the excellent 8-core AMD Zen4 8745HS that puts out 2595/12985 in Geekbench (~M4 multi-core numbers!), and runs our HEY test suite with 30,000 assertions almost as fast as an M4 Max! At that price, you get 32GB RAM + 1TB NVMe, as well as a DisplayPort, so &lt;a href=&quot;https://manuals.omamix.org/3/omacom/75/apple-displays-on-linux&quot;&gt;it works&lt;/a&gt; with both the Apple 5K Studio Display and the Apple 6K XDR Display (you just need &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BNX7MS6N&quot;&gt;the right cable&lt;/a&gt;). Main drawback is limited wifi/bluetooth range, but Beelink tells me there&#39;s a fix on the way for that.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;For $929, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bee-link.com/products/beelink-ser9-ai-9-hx-370&quot;&gt;you can get the SER9 HX370&lt;/a&gt;. This is the top dog in this form factor. It uses the incredible 12-core AMD Zen5 HX370 that hits 2990/15611 in Geekbench, and runs our HEY test suite faster than any Apple M chip I&#39;ve ever tested. The built-in graphics are also very capable. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XQpsWijbj4U&amp;amp;t=7m10s&quot;&gt;Enough to play a ton of games at 1080p&lt;/a&gt;. It also sorted the SER8&#39;s current wifi/bluetooth range issue.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I ran the SER8 as my main computer for a while, but now I&#39;m using the SER9, and I just about never feel like I need anything more. Yes, the Framework Desktop, with its insane AMD Max 395+ chip, is even more bonkers. It almost cuts the HEY test suite time in half(!), but it&#39;s also $1,795, and not yet generally available. (But &lt;a href=&quot;https://frame.work/desktop&quot;&gt;preorders are open&lt;/a&gt; for the ballers!).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Whichever machine fits your budget, it&#39;s frankly incredible that we have this kind of performance and efficiency available at these prices with all of these Beelinks drawing less than 10 watt at idle and no more than 100 watt at peak!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;So it&#39;s no wonder that Beelink has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/rsstafford/status/1946625692684243202&quot;&gt;selling&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/mitchellh/status/1943737627087450141&quot;&gt;these&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/matsonj/status/1947844912139145448&quot;&gt;units&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/codejake/status/1944972888161026425&quot;&gt;like&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/mani_bono/status/1940881681382244426&quot;&gt;hotcakes&lt;/a&gt; since I &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/dhh/status/1935500668992921731&quot;&gt;started&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/dhh/status/1941891417057685754&quot;&gt;talking&lt;/a&gt; about them on X as the ideal, cheap &lt;a href=&quot;https://omarchy.org&quot;&gt;Omarchy&lt;/a&gt; desktop computers. It&#39;s such a symbiotic relationship. There are a ton of programmers who have become Linux curious, and Beelink offers no-brainer options to give that a try at a bargain.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I just love when that happens. The perfect intersection of hardware, software, and timing. That&#39;s what we got here. It&#39;s a Beelink, baby!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(And no, before you ask, I don&#39;t get any royalties, there&#39;s no affiliate link, and I don&#39;t own any shares in Beelink. I just love discovering great technology and seeing people start their Linux journey with an awesome, affordable computer!)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary>
    <title>It&#39;s a Beelink, baby</title>
    <updated>2025-07-23T18:05:06Z</updated>
    <dc:date>2025-07-23T18:05:06Z</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>David Heinemeier Hansson</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:world.hey.com,2005:World::Post/43947</id>
    <link href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/linux-crosses-magic-market-share-threshold-in-us-1f914771"/>
    <published>2025-07-16T17:31:52Z</published>
    <summary>&lt;div class=&quot;trix-content&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;According to Statcounter, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ostechnix.com/linux-reaches-5-desktop-market-share-in-usa/&quot;&gt;Linux has claimed 5% market share of desktop computing in the US&lt;/a&gt;. That&#39;s double of where it was &lt;a href=&quot;https://gs.statcounter.com/os-market-share/desktop/united-states-of-america/#monthly-202207-202507&quot;&gt;just three years ago&lt;/a&gt;! Really impressive.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;Windows is still dominant at 63%, and Apple sit at 26%. But for the latter, it&#39;s quite a drop from their peak of 33% in June 2023.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;These are just browser stats, though (even if it&#39;s backed up by &lt;a href=&quot;https://radar.cloudflare.com/explorer?dataSet=http&amp;amp;groupBy=os&amp;amp;dt=52w&amp;amp;filters=deviceType%253DDesktop%252CbotClass%253DLikely_Human&amp;amp;loc=US&quot;&gt;directionally-similar numbers from Cloudflare&lt;/a&gt;). There&#39;s undoubtedly some variability in the numbers, by the season, and by what lives in the relatively large 4% mystery box of &quot;other&quot;. But there&#39;s no denying that Linux is trending in the right direction in the US.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;As a Dane, though, I find it sad that &lt;a href=&quot;https://gs.statcounter.com/os-market-share/desktop/denmark/#monthly-202001-202507&quot;&gt;Denmark is once again a laggard&lt;/a&gt; when it comes to adoption. Windows is even more dominant there at almost 70% (with Apple at 15%). Linux is just under 2%. Interestingly, though, ChromeOS, which is basically a locked-down Linux distribution, is at almost 5%.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I guess I really shouldn&#39;t be disappointed because this is how it always was. It was a big reason why I moved to the US back in 2005. When Ruby on Rails was taking off, it was in America first and foremost. Danish companies were too conservative, too complacent, too married to Microsoft to really pay attention.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;There are &lt;a href=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/denmark-gets-more-serious-about-digital-sovereignty-7736f756&quot;&gt;early indications&lt;/a&gt; that a willingness to change this laggard mentality might be sprouting, but we&#39;ve yet to see any evidence that a shift has actually taken hold yet. It&#39;s hard to change culture!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;So while the Danes continue to fiddle, the Americans continue to push forward. Linux is on the up and up!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary>
    <title>Linux crosses magic market share threshold in US</title>
    <updated>2025-07-16T17:31:52Z</updated>
    <dc:date>2025-07-16T17:31:52Z</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>David Heinemeier Hansson</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:world.hey.com,2005:World::Post/43798</id>
    <link href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/get-in-losers-we-re-moving-to-linux-5e1b93cd"/>
    <published>2025-07-03T22:26:17Z</published>
    <summary>&lt;div class=&quot;trix-content&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;I&#39;ve never seen so many developers curious about leaving the Mac and giving Linux a go. Something has really changed in the last few years. Maybe Linux just got better? Maybe &lt;a href=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/cheap-mini-pcs-have-gotten-really-good-c70ab40f&quot;&gt;powerful mini PCs&lt;/a&gt; made it easier? Maybe Apple just fumbled their relationship with developers &lt;a href=&quot;https://mobilegamer.biz/apples-new-eu-app-store-rules-are-insane-intentionally-confusing-and-blatantly-unlawful-say-pundits/&quot;&gt;one too many times&lt;/a&gt;? Maybe it&#39;s all of it. But whatever the reason, the vibe shift is noticeable.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;This is why the future is so hard to predict! People have been joking about &quot;The Year of Linux on the Desktop&quot; since the late 90s. Just like self-driving cars were supposed to be a thing back in 2017. And now, in the year of our Lord 2025, it seems like &lt;a href=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/self-driving-is-finally-happening-1d973fdd&quot;&gt;we&#39;re getting both&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I also wouldn&#39;t underestimate the cultural influence of a few key people. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pVI_smLgTY0&quot;&gt;PewDiePie sharing his journey into Arch and Hyprland with his 110 million followers&lt;/a&gt; is important. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZH3iKbEiks0&quot;&gt;ThePrimeagen moving to Arch and Hyprland&lt;/a&gt; is important. Typecraft teaching beginners &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2CP_9-jCV6A&quot;&gt;how to build an Arch and Hyprland setup from scratch&lt;/a&gt; is important (and who &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zikJTpJgzzo&quot;&gt;I just spoke to about Omarchy&lt;/a&gt;). Gabe Newell&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/steamdeck&quot;&gt;Steam Deck&lt;/a&gt; being built on Arch and pushing Proton to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protondb.com/explore?selectedFilters=whitelisted&quot;&gt;over 20,000 compatible Linux games&lt;/a&gt; is important.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;You&#39;ll notice a trend here, which is that &lt;a href=&quot;https://archlinux.org/&quot;&gt;Arch Linux&lt;/a&gt;, a notoriously &quot;difficult&quot; distribution, is at the center of much of this new engagement. Despite the fact that it&#39;s been around since 2003! There&#39;s nothing new about Arch, but there&#39;s something new about the circles of people it&#39;s engaging.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I&#39;ve put Arch at the center of &lt;a href=&quot;https://omarchy.org&quot;&gt;Omarchy&lt;/a&gt; too. Originally just because that was what &lt;a href=&quot;https://hypr.land/&quot;&gt;Hyprland&lt;/a&gt; recommended. Then, after living with the wonders of 90,000+ packages on the community-driven &lt;a href=&quot;https://aur.archlinux.org/&quot;&gt;AUR package repository&lt;/a&gt;, for its own sake. It&#39;s really good!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;But while Arch (and Hyprland) are having a moment amongst a new crowd, it&#39;s also &quot;just&quot; Linux at its core. And Linux really is the star of the show. The perfect, free, and open alternative that was just sitting around waiting for developers to finally have had enough of the commercial offerings from Apple and Microsoft.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;Now obviously there&#39;s a taste of &quot;new vegan sees vegans everywhere&quot; here. You start talking about Linux, and you&#39;ll hear from folks already in the community or those considering the move too. It&#39;s easy to confuse what you&#39;d like to be true with what is actually true.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;And it&#39;s definitely true that Linux is still a niche operating system on the desktop. Even among developers. Apple and Microsoft sit on the lion&#39;s share of the market share. But the mind share? They&#39;ve been losing that fast.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The window is open for a major shift to happen. First gradually, then suddenly. It feels like morning in Linux land!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary>
    <title>Get in losers, we&#39;re moving to Linux!</title>
    <updated>2025-07-03T22:26:17Z</updated>
    <dc:date>2025-07-03T22:26:17Z</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>David Heinemeier Hansson</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:world.hey.com,2005:World::Post/43692</id>
    <link href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/self-driving-is-finally-happening-1d973fdd"/>
    <published>2025-06-27T15:21:37Z</published>
    <summary>&lt;div class=&quot;trix-content&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;I still remember how the car industry got all excited back in 2017 about how steering wheels would soon be obsolete. Every concept car then was a living room on wheels, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4TAoqHwRi9k&quot;&gt;seats facing inwards&lt;/a&gt;. The self-driving revolution was imminent, they said. Well, it wasn&#39;t... but now it actually is!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Humans have a hard time with scenarios like this. If you promise them the moon in eight months, but don&#39;t end up delivering until eight years later, most will justifiably be skeptical that it&#39;s actually here — even in the face of gushing anecdotes and video evidence. That&#39;s the problem with delayed promises.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;So when Jason told me Tesla&#39;s self-driving tech was finally ready and real, I was indeed skeptical. I tried FSD as late as last year, and I didn&#39;t enjoy it much. Impressive in many ways, but too jerky. Too many interventions. How much could it really have improved in nine months or so? A lot, it turns out.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;We started the drive from Jason&#39;s house, and I watched him not once touch the pedals or steering wheel while we drove half an hour to the other end of town. Then repeated the feat on the way back. But that wasn&#39;t even the most impressive part. What really blew my mind was how dramatically better the fluidity of driving with FSD has become.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;His new Model Y anticipated the red light with the manners of a drives-for-the-queen-level chauffeur. And the way it knew exactly how to slow down to prevent a jerky movement when taking an incline into an elevated parking lot? Sublime.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;Elon, that son of a bitch, seems to have done it again! Proven everyone wrong. Proven me wrong. The self-driving dream has flipped from vaporware to credible near-term reality. All without LiDAR. AI really delivering on this one.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary>
    <title>Self-driving is finally happening</title>
    <updated>2025-06-27T15:21:37Z</updated>
    <dc:date>2025-06-27T15:21:37Z</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>David Heinemeier Hansson</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:world.hey.com,2005:World::Post/43686</id>
    <link href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/omarchy-is-out-4666dd31"/>
    <published>2025-06-26T23:07:19Z</published>
    <summary>&lt;div class=&quot;trix-content&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;My latest love letter to Linux has been published. It&#39;s called &lt;a href=&quot;https://omarchy.org/&quot;&gt;Omarchy&lt;/a&gt;, and it&#39;s an opinionated setup of &lt;a href=&quot;https://archlinux.org/&quot;&gt;the Arch Linux distribution&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://hypr.land/&quot;&gt;the Hyprland tiling window manager&lt;/a&gt;. With everything configured out-of-the-box to give you exactly the same setup that I now run every day. My Platonic ideal of what a developer environment should look like.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;It&#39;s not for everyone, though. Arch has a reputation for being difficult, but while I think that&#39;s vastly overstated, I still think it&#39;s fair to say that Ubuntu is an easier landing for someone new to Linux. And that&#39;s why this exists as a sister project to &lt;a href=&quot;https://omakub.org&quot;&gt;Omakub&lt;/a&gt; — my opinionated setup for Ubuntu — and not a replacement of it.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;Because I do think that Hyprland deserves its reputation of being difficult! Not because the core tiling window manager is hard, but because it comes incredibly bare-boned in the box. You have to figure out everything yourself. Even how to get a lock screen or idle timing or a menu bar or bluetooth setting or... you get the idea.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Omarchy is an attempt to solve for all that. To give you a default set of great, beautiful configurations for Hyprland, and installing all the common tooling you&#39;d normally want. You could setup this, not change a thing, and you&#39;ll have exactly what I run every day.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;But you can also just use this as a paved path into the glorious world of Linux ricing. The flip side of Hyprland being so atomized is that it&#39;s infinitely configurable. You can really, really make it yours. No wonder its the preferred platform for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/unixporn/&quot;&gt;r/unixporn&lt;/a&gt;, and even &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pVI_smLgTY0&quot;&gt;what PewDiePie picked up&lt;/a&gt; for his amazing Russian nuclear core build.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;I don&#39;t know when we&#39;ll literally get &quot;The Year of Linux on the Desktop&quot;, but I&#39;ve never been as convinced that its coming as I am now. There&#39;s enough dissent in the water. Enough dissatisfaction with both Apple and Microsoft.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;And between Valve going all-in on Steam on Linux (the Steamdeck runs Arch!), major creators (like PewDiePie) switching to Linux, and incredible projects like Hyprland — which offer not just a cheap visual copy of the two major commercial operating systems, but something much more unique and compelling — I think all the factors are in place for a big switch. At least among developers.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;But broad adoption or not, I&#39;m in love with Linux, and thrilled to share my work to make it easier to enjoy.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-gallery attachment-gallery--2&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;attachment attachment--preview attachment--lightboxable attachment--png&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a download=&quot;image.png&quot; title=&quot;Download image.png&quot; data-click-proxy-target=&quot;lightbox_link_blob_2170428413&quot; href=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/4666dd31/blobs/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6MjE3MDQyODQxMywicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ--e7af169ff03e28f13d4ebd1e85c7dbca861054b25abac92ef6fe562b708fbd22/image.png?disposition=attachment&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/4666dd31/representations/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6MjE3MDQyODQxMywicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ--e7af169ff03e28f13d4ebd1e85c7dbca861054b25abac92ef6fe562b708fbd22/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6eyJmb3JtYXQiOiJwbmciLCJyZXNpemVfdG9fbGltaXQiOlsxNjAwLDEyMDBdLCJxdWFsaXR5Ijo2MCwibG9hZGVyIjp7InBhZ2UiOm51bGx9LCJjb2FsZXNjZSI6dHJ1ZX0sInB1ciI6InZhcmlhdGlvbiJ9fQ--8a4eadc39996b456981c13ce71a114e6d921a6725bb1a424222e8cbff9ed0cc8/image.png&quot; alt=&quot;image.png&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;attachment attachment--preview attachment--lightboxable attachment--png&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a download=&quot;image.png&quot; title=&quot;Download image.png&quot; data-click-proxy-target=&quot;lightbox_link_blob_2170428909&quot; href=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/4666dd31/blobs/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6MjE3MDQyODkwOSwicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ--4627d9d22d55a0606881ddc401e92d0c91e11f15238576c0c03ca136019bf248/image.png?disposition=attachment&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/4666dd31/representations/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6MjE3MDQyODkwOSwicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ--4627d9d22d55a0606881ddc401e92d0c91e11f15238576c0c03ca136019bf248/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6eyJmb3JtYXQiOiJwbmciLCJyZXNpemVfdG9fbGltaXQiOlsxNjAwLDEyMDBdLCJxdWFsaXR5Ijo2MCwibG9hZGVyIjp7InBhZ2UiOm51bGx9LCJjb2FsZXNjZSI6dHJ1ZX0sInB1ciI6InZhcmlhdGlvbiJ9fQ--8a4eadc39996b456981c13ce71a114e6d921a6725bb1a424222e8cbff9ed0cc8/image.png&quot; alt=&quot;image.png&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-gallery attachment-gallery--2&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;attachment attachment--preview attachment--lightboxable attachment--png&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a download=&quot;image.png&quot; title=&quot;Download image.png&quot; data-click-proxy-target=&quot;lightbox_link_blob_2170429104&quot; href=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/4666dd31/blobs/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6MjE3MDQyOTEwNCwicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ--60116de216c2c3ef09b3e55cf4a41a42258d2052ab452807fd70a757275dafdb/image.png?disposition=attachment&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/4666dd31/representations/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6MjE3MDQyOTEwNCwicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ--60116de216c2c3ef09b3e55cf4a41a42258d2052ab452807fd70a757275dafdb/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6eyJmb3JtYXQiOiJwbmciLCJyZXNpemVfdG9fbGltaXQiOlsxNjAwLDEyMDBdLCJxdWFsaXR5Ijo2MCwibG9hZGVyIjp7InBhZ2UiOm51bGx9LCJjb2FsZXNjZSI6dHJ1ZX0sInB1ciI6InZhcmlhdGlvbiJ9fQ--8a4eadc39996b456981c13ce71a114e6d921a6725bb1a424222e8cbff9ed0cc8/image.png&quot; alt=&quot;image.png&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;attachment attachment--preview attachment--lightboxable attachment--png&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a download=&quot;image.png&quot; title=&quot;Download image.png&quot; data-click-proxy-target=&quot;lightbox_link_blob_2170429311&quot; href=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/4666dd31/blobs/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6MjE3MDQyOTMxMSwicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ--913afad5b22f70898ac0f210b1cce18c37772207f51533e2f44dc20739b38fab/image.png?disposition=attachment&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/4666dd31/representations/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6MjE3MDQyOTMxMSwicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ--913afad5b22f70898ac0f210b1cce18c37772207f51533e2f44dc20739b38fab/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6eyJmb3JtYXQiOiJwbmciLCJyZXNpemVfdG9fbGltaXQiOlsxNjAwLDEyMDBdLCJxdWFsaXR5Ijo2MCwibG9hZGVyIjp7InBhZ2UiOm51bGx9LCJjb2FsZXNjZSI6dHJ1ZX0sInB1ciI6InZhcmlhdGlvbiJ9fQ--8a4eadc39996b456981c13ce71a114e6d921a6725bb1a424222e8cbff9ed0cc8/image.png&quot; alt=&quot;image.png&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary>
    <title>Omarchy is out</title>
    <updated>2025-06-26T23:07:19Z</updated>
    <dc:date>2025-06-26T23:07:19Z</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>David Heinemeier Hansson</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:world.hey.com,2005:World::Post/43389</id>
    <link href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/denmark-gets-more-serious-about-digital-sovereignty-7736f756"/>
    <published>2025-06-03T08:05:41Z</published>
    <summary>&lt;div class=&quot;trix-content&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;The recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/icc-trump-sanctions-karim-khan-court-a4b4c02751ab84c09718b1b95cbd5db3&quot;&gt;disconnection of the ICC&#39;s chief prosecutor&lt;/a&gt;, at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/02/imposing-sanctions-on-the-international-criminal-court/&quot;&gt;the behest&lt;/a&gt; of the American administration, could not have come at a worse time for Microsoft. Just a month prior, the folks from Redmond &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.microsoft.com/on-the-issues/2025/04/30/european-digital-commitments/&quot;&gt;tried to assure Europe&lt;/a&gt; that all was well. That any speculation Europeans could get cut off from critical digital infrastructure was just fear, doubt, and uncertainty. Then everything Europeans worried could happen happened in Hague. Oops!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Microsoft&#39;s assurances met reality and reality won.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;That reality is that all American administrations have the power to disconnect any individual, company, or foreign government from digital infrastructure provided by American Big Tech. So in that sense, it&#39;s pointless to blame Microsoft for the sanctioning power vested in the Oval Office. But we certainly can blame them for gaslighting Europe about the risk.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;What&#39;s more important than apportioning blame, though, is getting out of the bind that Europe is in. The continent is hopelessly dependent on American Big Tech for even the most basic of digital infrastructure. If this American administration, or the next, decides to use its sanctioning power again, Europe is in a real pickle. And with the actions taken against the ICC in Haag, Europe would be negligent to ignore the threat.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Denmark even more so. It&#39;s no secret that tensions between Denmark and the US are at a historic high. Trump keeps repeating &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newsweek.com/trump-greenland-denmark-mette-frederiksen-nato-russia-china-2077596&quot;&gt;a desire to take over Greenland&lt;/a&gt; by fuzzy means possible. The American intelligence services have been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/world/greenland-spying-us-intelligence-809c4ef2&quot;&gt;directed to increase their spying&lt;/a&gt; on Denmark and Greenland. Naturally, the Danes are spooked. They should be!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Regardless of what happens with Greenland, trade negotiations, or geopolitical disagreements, though, it would suit Europe well to become digitally sovereign. That doesn&#39;t mean cutting off all American tech, but it does mean rejecting any services that can be turned off from Washington. So in terms of Microsoft, it means no more Microsoft 365, no more Teams, no more Azure.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;And that&#39;s exactly what the two biggest counties in Denmark have announced plans to do. Copenhagen and Aarhus just declared that &lt;a href=&quot;https://politiken.dk/viden/tech/art10411353/Nu-er-det-nok-K%C3%B8benhavn-og-Aarhus-vil-g%C3%B8re-sig-uafh%C3%A6ngige-af-Microsoft?shareToken=tKwKubAE1XVA&quot;&gt;they&#39;re going to get rid of Microsoft products&lt;/a&gt; for all their workers. The Copenhagen county is the largest employer in Denmark with over 40,000 employees. So this is a big deal!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The chairman of the Copenhagen committee who pushed this forward made this comment to Danish media:&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;em&gt;If, theoretically, the relationship to the US gets worse, we could fear that Microsoft would be forced to shut everything down. That possibility exists. And if we suddenly can&#39;t access our emails or communicate via our systems, we&#39;ll be challenged.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;That&#39;s an understatement. Denmark is one of the most highly digitalized countries in the world. It&#39;s also one of the most Microsoft dependent. In fact, Microsoft is by far and away the single biggest dependency, so it makes perfect sense to start the quest for digital sovereignty there.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;But Denmark is also full of unambitious, defeatist bureaucrats who can&#39;t imagine a world without Microsoft. Just today, the IT director for The Capital Region &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.version2.dk/artikel/it-direktoer-tror-ikke-paa-microsoft-exit-det-er-utopi-danmark-kan-udvikle-alternativer&quot;&gt;declared it to utopian to think Denmark could ever achieve digital sovereignty or meaningfully replace Microsoft&lt;/a&gt;. Not even a decade would make a dent, says the director, while recognizing that if we&#39;d done something 15 years ago, we wouldn&#39;t be in this pickle. A remarkable illustration of cognitive dissonance!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;Sadly, this is not an uncommon conclusion from people who work inside the belly of bureaucracies for too long. Whatever has always done too often seems like the only thing that ever could be done. But, as Mandela said, it always seems impossible until it&#39;s done.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;So let&#39;s get it done. Digital sovereignty isn&#39;t easy, but neither was securing a sovereign energy supply. Nor will it be to rebuild a credible defensive military. Europe needs all of it, yesterday. The bureaucrats who aren&#39;t interested in making it happen should find employment elsewhere.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary>
    <title>Denmark gets more serious about digital sovereignty</title>
    <updated>2025-06-03T08:05:41Z</updated>
    <dc:date>2025-06-03T08:05:41Z</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>David Heinemeier Hansson</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:world.hey.com,2005:World::Post/43376</id>
    <link href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/omarchy-bottling-that-inspiration-before-it-spoils-cd75e26b"/>
    <published>2025-06-02T15:07:56Z</published>
    <summary>&lt;div class=&quot;trix-content&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;Over the years, I&#39;ve learned not to question inspiration. To simply let it drive when it shows up with a full tank. Quite often, I don&#39;t exactly know where we&#39;re going or even why we&#39;re going, but it&#39;s repeatedly taken me to just the right place at just the right time, so now I just hop in and say: Let&#39;s go!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;Case in point: &lt;a href=&quot;https://archlinux.org/&quot;&gt;Arch&lt;/a&gt; + &lt;a href=&quot;https://hyprland.org/&quot;&gt;Hyprland&lt;/a&gt;. It&#39;s been over a year since I created &lt;a href=&quot;https://omakub.org/&quot;&gt;Omakub&lt;/a&gt; to smooth out my own exit path from macOS to Linux, and in the process, helped thousands of others enjoy a beautiful, preconfigured, and relatively familiar desktop experience with Ubuntu. And I continue to think this is an excellent choice for Linux, especially for first-time Mac and Windows defectors.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;But this weekend, I just happened to be home alone, and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2CP_9-jCV6A&quot;&gt;hype&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UzUu77RZGSE&quot;&gt;around&lt;/a&gt; Arch + Hyprland got the better of me. While Ubuntu is all about being a friendly place for newcomers to Linux, Arch + Hyprland is the exact opposite: It&#39;s Linux on hard mode!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;At least that&#39;s the reputation, and there&#39;s certainly something to that. The Arch ISO literally just dumps you into a terminal with scarcely any direction. Just getting on the Wi-Fi requires learning the arcane command-line options for the iwctl terminal configurator.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;But besides iwctl, it&#39;s actually not that bad anymore. We now have a cheat code for installing Arch in the form of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y9nKjTfDHLA&quot;&gt;archinstall&lt;/a&gt;. It&#39;s a terminal interface for getting all the bits like picking a disk and creating the first user done in the correct order, without having to set aside an entire evening just to get the OS installed. So it didn&#39;t take long to get Arch up and running.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;That doesn&#39;t get you much further, though! By default, Arch is about as minimal as it gets. There&#39;s no default graphical interface. There are no niceties. Not even wget or curl by default! It really is just a bare-bones installation of Linux.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;But on the other hand, Arch is blessed with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.archlinux.org/title/Arch_User_Repository&quot;&gt;AUR&lt;/a&gt; — a Wikipedia-style, community-maintained package management system that seems to have literally every piece of software ever released on Linux, and always in the latest version.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;A quarter of Omakub is trying to work around the fact that helpful tools like Alacritty or LazyGit or whatever rarely have official packages for Ubuntu, so you&#39;re left doing a lot of manual scripting to get everything a developer would want from a modern Linux setup. Not so with the AUR!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;So that&#39;s Arch. But Hyprland is even more hilarious. It&#39;s a tiling window manager with something as rare in the Linux world as a keen focus on aesthetics! It looks like it was written by visual artists rather than neckbeards. And it&#39;s at the core of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/unixporn/top/?t=all&quot;&gt;the modern r/unixporn Linux ricing subculture&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;That&#39;s not the funny part, though. The funny part is how ridiculously atomized the entire thing is. Hyprland comes with absolutely nothing out of the box. No login screen, no menu bar, no notification system, no file manager, no visual settings application. Just a text-based configuration file, a wiki, and an outline on a map for how to design your own adventure.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;This means that if you&#39;re interested in running Hyprland, and you intend to set it all up from scratch, you&#39;re probably signing up for at least a good 10+ hours — just to install and configure everything! Now, there are some precompiled setup scripts out there already, but most of them still require you to do a ton of manual legwork before you reach that beautiful summit of a complete system.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;So while the downside of Arch + Hyprland is that literally every last detail requires you to make a choice and a config file to move on, it&#39;s also its upside: you can change EVERYTHING! And the core window tiling magic of Hyprland is one of the most intoxicating ways of using a computer that I&#39;ve ever experienced. It looks amazing; it feels amazing (if you prefer using a keyboard instead of a mouse!).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;I&#39;ve poured hours and hours into this quest over the weekend, and yet I&#39;m still not even done with my first Arch + Hyprland build! My login screen looks like shit. I haven&#39;t decided on a final menu bar configuration. But what is working — the basic tiling flow and look — is so nice that the inspiration keeps driving the project forward.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Which, of course, I&#39;ve already decided to codify. I&#39;m not going through all this work to set up a beautiful, preconfigured, fully-functional, out-of-the-box Arch + Hyprland combo and then not share it with anyone who&#39;s curious (and might not have 10–20 hours for this kind of side quest available in their schedule). So of course I registered a domain and found a way to draw some ASCII art: &lt;a href=&quot;https://omarchy.org&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Omarchy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is on the way!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;attachment attachment--preview attachment--lightboxable attachment--png&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a download=&quot;image.png&quot; title=&quot;Download image.png&quot; data-click-proxy-target=&quot;lightbox_link_blob_2140598971&quot; href=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/cd75e26b/blobs/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6MjE0MDU5ODk3MSwicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ--b86966afc12307c2502d3bc3ccec19861da09d446c6a2da89c960ff5047f4d7b/image.png?disposition=attachment&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/cd75e26b/representations/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6MjE0MDU5ODk3MSwicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ--b86966afc12307c2502d3bc3ccec19861da09d446c6a2da89c960ff5047f4d7b/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6eyJmb3JtYXQiOiJwbmciLCJyZXNpemVfdG9fbGltaXQiOlszODQwLDI1NjBdLCJxdWFsaXR5Ijo2MCwibG9hZGVyIjp7InBhZ2UiOm51bGx9LCJjb2FsZXNjZSI6dHJ1ZX0sInB1ciI6InZhcmlhdGlvbiJ9fQ--7edc7b21f6fad97fa22412618822c4d19725431f296c7ce47dc174b61535d27c/image.png&quot; alt=&quot;image.png&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary>
    <title>Omarchy: Bottling that inspiration before it spoils</title>
    <updated>2025-06-07T19:21:10Z</updated>
    <dc:date>2025-06-07T19:21:10Z</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>David Heinemeier Hansson</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:world.hey.com,2005:World::Post/43187</id>
    <link href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/hey-is-finally-for-sale-on-the-iphone-a08cb218"/>
    <published>2025-05-20T13:52:09Z</published>
    <summary>&lt;div class=&quot;trix-content&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hey.com/apple/&quot;&gt;Our battle with Apple&lt;/a&gt; over &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/dhh/status/1272968382329942017&quot;&gt;their gangster attempt&lt;/a&gt; to extort 30% of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hey.com/&quot;&gt;HEY&lt;/a&gt; revenues was one of the defining moments of my career. It was the kind of test that calls you to account for what you believe and asks what you&#39;re willing to risk to see it through. Well, we risked everything, but also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hey.com/apple/path/&quot;&gt;secured a four-year truce&lt;/a&gt;, and now &lt;a href=&quot;https://9to5mac.com/2025/05/01/epic-win-apple-link-out-to-web-free-reign/&quot;&gt;near-total victory&lt;/a&gt; is at hand: &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/hey-email/id1506603805&quot;&gt;HEY is finally for sale on the iPhone in the US!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;Credit for this amazing turn of events goes to Epic Games founders &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/TimSweeneyEpic&quot;&gt;Tim Sweeney&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/MarkRein&quot;&gt;Mark Rein&lt;/a&gt;, who did what no small developer like us could ever dream of doing: they &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macrumors.com/2025/05/06/epic-games-legal-fees/&quot;&gt;spent over $100 million to sue Apple&lt;/a&gt; in court. And while the first round yielded very little progress, Apple&#39;s (&lt;a href=&quot;https://fingfx.thomsonreuters.com/gfx/legaldocs/zjpqagqoypx/Epic%20v%20Apple%20-%20referral%20order%20-%20Gonzalez%20Rogers%2020250430.pdf&quot;&gt;possibly criminal&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/boards-policy-regulation/us-judge-rules-apple-violated-order-reform-app-store-2025-04-30/&quot;&gt;contempt of court&lt;/a&gt; is what ultimately &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macrumors.com/2025/04/30/apple-app-store-anti-steering-injunction-violation/&quot;&gt;delivered the resolution&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks to their fight for Fortnite, app developers everywhere are now allowed to link out of apps to their own web-based payment system in the US store (but, sadly, nowhere else yet).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;This is all we ever wanted from Apple: to have a way to distribute our iPhone apps and keep the customer relationship by billing directly. The 30% toll gets all the attention, and it is ludicrously egregious, but to us, it&#39;s just as much about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hey.com/apple/iap/&quot;&gt;retaining that direct customer relationship&lt;/a&gt;, so we can help folks with refunds, so they don&#39;t tie their billing for a multi-platform email system to a single manufacturer.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;Apple always claims to put the needs of the users first, and that whatever hardship developers have to carry is justified by their customer-focused obsession. But in this case, it&#39;s clear that the obsession was with collecting the easiest billions Apple has ever made, by taking an obscene cut of all software and subscription sales on the platform.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;This obsession with squeezing every last dollar from developers has produced countless customer-hostile experiences on the iPhone. Like how you couldn&#39;t buy a book in the Kindle app before this (now you can!). Or sign up for a Netflix subscription (now you can!). Before, users would hunt in vain for an explanation inside these apps, and thanks to Apple&#39;s gag orders, developers were not even allowed to explain the confusing situation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;It&#39;s been the same deal with HEY. While we successfully fought off Apple&#39;s attempt to extort us into using their in-app payment system (IAP), we&#39;ve been stuck with an awkward user experience ever since. One that prevented new customers from signing up for a real email address in the application, and instead sent them down this bizarre burner-account setup. All so the app would &quot;do something&quot;, in order to please an argument that App Store chief &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/18/interview-apples-schiller-says-position-on-hey-app-is-unchanged-and-no-rules-changes-are-imminent/?utm_source=chatgpt.com&quot;&gt;Phil Schiller made up on the fly in an interview&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;That&#39;s what we can now get rid of. No more weird burner accounts. Now you can sign up directly for a real email address in HEY, and if you like what we have to offer (and I think you will!), you&#39;ll be able to pay the $99/year for a subscription via a web-based flow that it&#39;s now kosher to link to from the app itself.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;What a journey, and what a needless torching of the developer relationship from Apple&#39;s side. We&#39;ve always been happy to pay Apple for hosting our application on the App Store, as all developers have always needed to do via the $99/year developer fee. But being forced to hand over 30% of the business, as well as the direct customer relationship, was always an unacceptable overreach.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Now that&#39;s been arrested by Judge Yvonne Gonzalez Rogers from the United States District Court of Northern California, who has delivered app developers the only real relief that we&#39;ve seen in this whole sordid monopoly affair that&#39;s been boiling since 2020. It&#39;s a beautiful thing.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;It also offers Apple an opportunity to bury the hatchet with developers. They can choose to accept the court&#39;s decision in full and worldwide. Allow developers everywhere the right to link to their own billing flow, so they can retain their own customer relationship, and so business models that can&#39;t carry a 30% toll can flourish.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;Besides, Apple&#39;s own offering will likely still have plenty of pull. I&#39;m sure many small developers would continue to consider IAP to avoid having to worry about international taxes or even direct customer service. Nobody is taking that away from Apple or those developers. All Judge Rogers is demanding is that Apple compete fairly with alternative arrangements.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;In case Apple doesn&#39;t accept the court&#39;s decision — and there&#39;s sadly &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/1924499498513862720/photo/1&quot;&gt;some evidence&lt;/a&gt; to that — I hope the European antitrust regulators watch the simple yet powerful mechanism that Judge Rogers has imposed on Apple. While I&#39;d love side loading as much as the next sovereign techie who wants to own the hardware I buy, I think we can get the lion&#39;s share of independence by simply being allowed to link out of the apps, just like has been so ordered by this District Court.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I do hope, though, that Apple does accept the court&#39;s decision. Both because it would be a stain on their reputation to get convicted of criminal contempt of court, but also because I really want Apple to return to being a shining city on the hill. To show that you can win in the market merely by making better products. Something Apple never used to be afraid of doing. That they don&#39;t need these gangster extortion techniques to make the numbers that Cook has promised Wall Street.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;Despite &lt;a href=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/the-year-on-linux-7f30279e&quot;&gt;moving on to Linux&lt;/a&gt; and Android, I have a real soft spot for Apple&#39;s taste, aesthetics, and engineering prowess. They&#39;ve lost their way and moral compass over the last half decade or so, but that&#39;s only one leadership pivot away from being found again. That won&#39;t win back all the trust and good faith that was squandered right away, but they&#39;ll at least be on the long road to recovery.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Who knows, maybe developers would even be inclined to assist Apple next time they &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2025/02/21/apples-vision-pro-has-a-problem-a-year-into-existence-too-few-apps.html&quot;&gt;need help launching a new device&lt;/a&gt; in need of third-party software to succeed.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-gallery attachment-gallery--3&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;attachment attachment--preview attachment--lightboxable attachment--png&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a download=&quot;signup-link-on-welcome-screen.png&quot; title=&quot;Download signup-link-on-welcome-screen.png&quot; data-click-proxy-target=&quot;lightbox_link_blob_2124846721&quot; href=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/a08cb218/blobs/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6MjEyNDg0NjcyMSwicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ--c096aaa1581ada74b15be5898c89385cd43a0b0a9b070f5ae7a7d0901d519a94/signup-link-on-welcome-screen.png?disposition=attachment&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/a08cb218/representations/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6MjEyNDg0NjcyMSwicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ--c096aaa1581ada74b15be5898c89385cd43a0b0a9b070f5ae7a7d0901d519a94/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6eyJmb3JtYXQiOiJwbmciLCJyZXNpemVfdG9fbGltaXQiOlsxNjAwLDEyMDBdLCJxdWFsaXR5Ijo2MCwibG9hZGVyIjp7InBhZ2UiOm51bGx9LCJjb2FsZXNjZSI6dHJ1ZX0sInB1ciI6InZhcmlhdGlvbiJ9fQ--8a4eadc39996b456981c13ce71a114e6d921a6725bb1a424222e8cbff9ed0cc8/signup-link-on-welcome-screen.png&quot; alt=&quot;signup-link-on-welcome-screen.png&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;attachment attachment--preview attachment--lightboxable attachment--png&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a download=&quot;show-price-before-signup.png&quot; title=&quot;Download show-price-before-signup.png&quot; data-click-proxy-target=&quot;lightbox_link_blob_2124846750&quot; href=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/a08cb218/blobs/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6MjEyNDg0Njc1MCwicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ--74ebd316df2223bf1bbf8134a3a19fb149a49ad72d7b163ed17ba073b3c99f69/show-price-before-signup.png?disposition=attachment&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/a08cb218/representations/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6MjEyNDg0Njc1MCwicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ--74ebd316df2223bf1bbf8134a3a19fb149a49ad72d7b163ed17ba073b3c99f69/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6eyJmb3JtYXQiOiJwbmciLCJyZXNpemVfdG9fbGltaXQiOlsxNjAwLDEyMDBdLCJxdWFsaXR5Ijo2MCwibG9hZGVyIjp7InBhZ2UiOm51bGx9LCJjb2FsZXNjZSI6dHJ1ZX0sInB1ciI6InZhcmlhdGlvbiJ9fQ--8a4eadc39996b456981c13ce71a114e6d921a6725bb1a424222e8cbff9ed0cc8/show-price-before-signup.png&quot; alt=&quot;show-price-before-signup.png&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;attachment attachment--preview attachment--lightboxable attachment--png&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a download=&quot;link-to-buy-inside-app.png&quot; title=&quot;Download link-to-buy-inside-app.png&quot; data-click-proxy-target=&quot;lightbox_link_blob_2124846822&quot; href=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/a08cb218/blobs/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6MjEyNDg0NjgyMiwicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ--96fc475f28bba7674c57eaf7a5b48a3950172d0f589338dc7023de426885ac3e/link-to-buy-inside-app.png?disposition=attachment&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/a08cb218/representations/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6MjEyNDg0NjgyMiwicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ--96fc475f28bba7674c57eaf7a5b48a3950172d0f589338dc7023de426885ac3e/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6eyJmb3JtYXQiOiJwbmciLCJyZXNpemVfdG9fbGltaXQiOlsxNjAwLDEyMDBdLCJxdWFsaXR5Ijo2MCwibG9hZGVyIjp7InBhZ2UiOm51bGx9LCJjb2FsZXNjZSI6dHJ1ZX0sInB1ciI6InZhcmlhdGlvbiJ9fQ--8a4eadc39996b456981c13ce71a114e6d921a6725bb1a424222e8cbff9ed0cc8/link-to-buy-inside-app.png&quot; alt=&quot;link-to-buy-inside-app.png&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-gallery attachment-gallery--3&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figure class=&quot;attachment attachment--preview attachment--lightboxable attachment--png&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a download=&quot;choose-to-pay-from-settings.png&quot; title=&quot;Download choose-to-pay-from-settings.png&quot; data-click-proxy-target=&quot;lightbox_link_blob_2124863682&quot; href=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/a08cb218/blobs/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6MjEyNDg2MzY4MiwicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ--2814ce6c67162d10299e18d4b6eb7c8f993ff44fdc7094d786c103e3f2340ecb/choose-to-pay-from-settings.png?disposition=attachment&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/a08cb218/representations/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6MjEyNDg2MzY4MiwicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ--2814ce6c67162d10299e18d4b6eb7c8f993ff44fdc7094d786c103e3f2340ecb/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6eyJmb3JtYXQiOiJwbmciLCJyZXNpemVfdG9fbGltaXQiOlsxNjAwLDEyMDBdLCJxdWFsaXR5Ijo2MCwibG9hZGVyIjp7InBhZ2UiOm51bGx9LCJjb2FsZXNjZSI6dHJ1ZX0sInB1ciI6InZhcmlhdGlvbiJ9fQ--8a4eadc39996b456981c13ce71a114e6d921a6725bb1a424222e8cbff9ed0cc8/choose-to-pay-from-settings.png&quot; alt=&quot;choose-to-pay-from-settings.png&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;attachment attachment--preview attachment--lightboxable attachment--png&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a download=&quot;external-cc-form.png&quot; title=&quot;Download external-cc-form.png&quot; data-click-proxy-target=&quot;lightbox_link_blob_2124846949&quot; href=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/a08cb218/blobs/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6MjEyNDg0Njk0OSwicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ--5fa11c43e7dfa68a4ec21e7556566795f38bd0415c78c80ee181f87f901bfd6b/external-cc-form.png?disposition=attachment&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/a08cb218/representations/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6MjEyNDg0Njk0OSwicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ--5fa11c43e7dfa68a4ec21e7556566795f38bd0415c78c80ee181f87f901bfd6b/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6eyJmb3JtYXQiOiJwbmciLCJyZXNpemVfdG9fbGltaXQiOlsxNjAwLDEyMDBdLCJxdWFsaXR5Ijo2MCwibG9hZGVyIjp7InBhZ2UiOm51bGx9LCJjb2FsZXNjZSI6dHJ1ZX0sInB1ciI6InZhcmlhdGlvbiJ9fQ--8a4eadc39996b456981c13ce71a114e6d921a6725bb1a424222e8cbff9ed0cc8/external-cc-form.png&quot; alt=&quot;external-cc-form.png&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;attachment attachment--preview attachment--lightboxable attachment--png&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a download=&quot;confirmation-of-purchase.png&quot; title=&quot;Download confirmation-of-purchase.png&quot; data-click-proxy-target=&quot;lightbox_link_blob_2124846971&quot; href=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/a08cb218/blobs/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6MjEyNDg0Njk3MSwicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ--3ca9c6c1a67f0c603c097bab8ef4cebd8799bc4c292dde4b05028f940c405bf1/confirmation-of-purchase.png?disposition=attachment&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/a08cb218/representations/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6MjEyNDg0Njk3MSwicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ--3ca9c6c1a67f0c603c097bab8ef4cebd8799bc4c292dde4b05028f940c405bf1/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6eyJmb3JtYXQiOiJwbmciLCJyZXNpemVfdG9fbGltaXQiOlsxNjAwLDEyMDBdLCJxdWFsaXR5Ijo2MCwibG9hZGVyIjp7InBhZ2UiOm51bGx9LCJjb2FsZXNjZSI6dHJ1ZX0sInB1ciI6InZhcmlhdGlvbiJ9fQ--8a4eadc39996b456981c13ce71a114e6d921a6725bb1a424222e8cbff9ed0cc8/confirmation-of-purchase.png&quot; alt=&quot;confirmation-of-purchase.png&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary>
    <title>HEY is finally for sale on the iPhone!</title>
    <updated>2025-05-20T13:52:09Z</updated>
    <dc:date>2025-05-20T13:52:09Z</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>David Heinemeier Hansson</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:world.hey.com,2005:World::Post/43158</id>
    <link href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/cheap-mini-pcs-have-gotten-really-good-c70ab40f"/>
    <published>2025-05-18T08:32:35Z</published>
    <summary>&lt;div class=&quot;trix-content&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;For the past week, I&#39;ve been working off the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.minisforum.com/products/minisforum-um680-um760-um870-slim?variant=49516307939634&quot;&gt;Minisforum UM870&lt;/a&gt;. A tiny mini PC with an 8-core/16-thread AMD 8745H CPU, which retails for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/MINISFORUM-Barebone-Computer-5-0GHz-Support/dp/B0DL5ZRQV3/&quot;&gt;$343&lt;/a&gt; (or &lt;a href=&quot;https://minisforumpc.eu/products/um680-760-870-slim-mini-pc?variant=51700059144558&quot;&gt;€379&lt;/a&gt;) as a bare-bone unit, and stays below $550, even after adding &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Crucial-5600MT-5200MT-4800MT-CT48G56C46S5/dp/B0C79LKJK4/&quot;&gt;48GB of RAM&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/WD_BLACK-SN850X-Internal-Gaming-Solid/dp/B0B7CKVCCV/&quot;&gt;1TB of storage&lt;/a&gt;. I&#39;m shocked to report that I really don&#39;t need more than this!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;I mean, I knew that Apple&#39;s Mac Mini, which is equally petite to the Minisforum, had plenty of power for macOS. But somehow I thought Apple had some special sauce that made this possible, and that PCs were forever condemned to be bigger, louder, and slower. How 2020 of me.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;The UM870 is a little beast. It runs our full HEY test suite in just 2m28s. In comparison, it takes a 14-core M4 Pro 2m49s, and such &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/shop/buy-mac/mac-mini/apple-m4-pro-chip-with-12-core-cpu-16-core-gpu-24gb-memory-512gb&quot;&gt;an Apple costs $2,199&lt;/a&gt;, once you&#39;ve given it 48GB of RAM and 1TB of storage.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;Now, that M4 Mac Mini can probably do things with, say, 8K video editing that the UM870 can&#39;t touch. But on the other hand, the UM870 can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xKD2mU6shdo&amp;amp;t=269s&quot;&gt;play the latest video games&lt;/a&gt;. Everything from Fortnite to Cyberpunk 2077 to Forza Horizon. It won&#39;t trouble a modern, dedicated Nvidia card for max FPS, but it&#39;s perfectly playable at 1080p at medium settings in a ton of games.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;In raw CPU power, the AMD 8745H will match a regular M4 in multi-core. They both clock in right around 13,000 points on Geekbench 6. Though the M4 is a fair bit quicker in single-core. The AMD is also far behind an M4 Pro in raw multi-core power (13K vs 22K), but at less than a quarter the cost, it&#39;s hard to complain.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;But as with the example of video games, it&#39;s often deceiving just to compare the Geekbench numbers, because it all depends on what you&#39;re doing. If you&#39;re really into video games, it&#39;s no use to have extra grunt, if your favorite games won&#39;t run. The same is true if you&#39;re a developer working with Docker containers and a Linux toolchain. As quoted above, the UM870 handily defeats the M4 Pro in our all-cores-buzzing HEY test suite.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;That&#39;s partly because we run databases and accessories, like MySQL, Redis, and ElasticSearch, in Docker containers. Even though we run the Ruby code natively on both platforms, the Docker dependencies put the Mac further behind than it otherwise would have been, because Linux runs Docker natively, and the Mac has to deal with the file-system tax and other drawbacks.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;The irony is that it was partly Apple&#39;s volume with and investment in TSMC that got us these incredible AMD chips, as they&#39;re riding the same improvements in TSMC manufacturing prowess as Apple&#39;s M chips. The Zen 4 cores in the 8745H are all forged on the same 5nm process as the M2, so it&#39;s no surprise that the AMD cores are dead-on-the-money for Apple&#39;s in Geekbench single-core performance.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;And Zen 4 is even the last generation! The insane new (and insanely named) AMD Ryzen AI Max 395+ chip that&#39;s used in the upcoming &lt;a href=&quot;https://frame.work/desktop&quot;&gt;Framework Desktop&lt;/a&gt; runs on Zen 5 cores. And with 16 of those, the 395+ is faster in Geekbench multi-core than an M4 Pro, and only ever so slightly behind the M4 Max. On my HEY test suite, it completes the run in an insane 1m21s — more than twice as fast as the 14-core M4 Pro!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;But I digress. The 395+ chip isn&#39;t cheap, even if it&#39;s still a great deal. The Framework Desktop with 64GB/1TB, which is twice as fast as the M4 Pro with our HEY tests, is $1,744. That&#39;s still less than the $2,199 Mac Mini, which only has 48GB of RAM. But obviously way more than a $550 Minisforum! And while it&#39;s quite small, it&#39;s not tiny, like the UM870.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;Regardless, this is what I love about technology. I love when our assumptions are tested: just how small and cheap can an awesome developer machine become? I love that open-source Linux is able to run laps around Apple in the workloads that many developers need (like working with Docker containers). I love that this tiny little silent $550 mini PC on my desk is capable of putting out computing power that only a decade ago would have been reserved to loud, honking metal in a data center.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Mini PCs have gotten really good. &lt;a href=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/amd-in-everything-0ec0cc6e&quot;&gt;AMD is on a roll&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/the-year-on-linux-7f30279e&quot;&gt;Linux is a blast&lt;/a&gt;. These are my conclusions. Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.minisforum.com/products/minisforum-um760-slim?variant=46040999624949&quot;&gt;Minisforum UM870&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bee-link.com/products/beelink-ser8-8745hs&quot;&gt;Beelink SER8&lt;/a&gt;. Anything with an AMD 7745H and up to an 8945HS should be a great deal. If you want to splurge (yet still get a bargain compared to the macs), you could have a look at the new HX370 in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bee-link.com/products/beelink-ser9-ai-9-hx-370&quot;&gt;Beelink SER9&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.minisforum.com/products/minisforum-ai-x1?variant=46484114014453&quot;&gt;Minisforum X1&lt;/a&gt;, but I&#39;d save my money, buy a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lofree.co/products/lofree-flow-the-smoothest-mechanical-keyboard&quot;&gt;Lofree Flow84&lt;/a&gt; keyboard to go with the new mini rig, and put the rest of the money towards a &lt;a href=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/what-is-hifi-dddab2ae&quot;&gt;KEF LSX II savings fund&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update: The MediaTek Wifi + Bluetooth card used in the UM870 isn&#39;t compatible with Ubuntu out of the box. I run everything hardwired for performance, so didn&#39;t notice during my testing, but a reader caught it, and I confirmed it. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;If you need wireless out-of-the-box on Ubuntu, I found that the card in the Beelink SER9 works great with both. If you already have a UM870 or still want one, and you need wireless, you could buy the AMD RZ616 Wi-Fi 6E card &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://frame.work/products/amd-rz616-wi-fi-6e?v=FRANRFFX01&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;from Framework&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; or &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/OKN-AX210NGW-Bluetooth-Wireless-Ultra-Low/dp/B08MJLPZPL/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amazon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; for around $20 — that works and slots right in.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary>
    <title>Cheap mini PCs have gotten really good</title>
    <updated>2025-05-25T09:54:41Z</updated>
    <dc:date>2025-05-25T09:54:41Z</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>David Heinemeier Hansson</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:world.hey.com,2005:World::Post/43116</id>
    <link href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/coding-should-be-a-vibe-50908f49"/>
    <published>2025-05-13T07:32:48Z</published>
    <summary>&lt;div class=&quot;trix-content&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;The appeal of &quot;vibe coding&quot; — where programmers lean back and prompt their way through an entire project with AI — appears partly to be based on the fact that so many development environments are deeply unpleasant to work with.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;So it&#39;s no wonder that all these programmers stuck working with cumbersome languages and frameworks can&#39;t wait to give up on the coding part of software development. If I found writing code a chore, I&#39;d be looking for retirement too.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;But I don&#39;t.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I mean, I used to! When I started programming, it was purely because I wanted programs. Learning to code was a necessary but inconvenient step toward bringing systems to life. That all changed when I learned Ruby and built Rails.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;Ruby&#39;s entire premise is &quot;programmer happiness&quot;: that writing code should be a joy. And historically, the language was willing to trade run-time performance, memory usage, and other machine sympathies against the pursuit of said programmer happiness. These days, it seems like you can eat your cake and have it too, though. Ruby, after thirty years of constant improvement, is now incredibly fast and efficient, yet remains a delight to work with.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;That ethos couldn&#39;t shine brighter now. Disgruntled programmers have finally realized that an escape from nasty syntax, boilerplate galore, and ecosystem hyper-churn is possible. That&#39;s the appeal of AI: having it hide away all that unpleasantness. Only it&#39;s like cleaning your room by stuffing the mess under the bed — it doesn&#39;t make it go away!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;But the instinct is correct: Programming &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be a vibe! It should be fun! It should resemble English closely enough that line noise doesn&#39;t obscure the underlying ideas and decisions. It should allow a richness of expression that serves the human reader instead of favoring the strictness preferred by the computer. Ruby does.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;And given that, I have no interest in giving up writing code. That&#39;s not the unpleasant part that I want AI to take off my hands. Just so I can — what? — become a project manager for a murder of AI crows? I&#39;ve had the option to retreat up the manager ladder for most of my career, but I&#39;ve steadily refused, because I really like writing Ruby! It&#39;s the most enjoyable part of the job!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;That doesn&#39;t mean AI doesn&#39;t have a role to play when writing Ruby. I&#39;m conversing and collaborating with LLMs all day long — looking up APIs, clarifying concepts, and asking stupid questions. AI is a superb pair programmer, but I&#39;d retire before permanently handing it the keyboard to drive the code.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Maybe one day, wanting to write code will be a quaint concept. Like tending to horses for transportation in the modern world — done as a hobby but devoid of any economic value.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I don&#39;t think anyone knows just how far we can push the intelligence and creativity of these insatiable token munchers. And I wouldn&#39;t bet against their advance, but it&#39;s clear to me that a big part of their appeal to programmers is the wisdom that Ruby was founded on: Programming should favor and flatter the human.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary>
    <title>Coding should be a vibe!</title>
    <updated>2025-05-13T07:32:48Z</updated>
    <dc:date>2025-05-13T07:32:48Z</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>David Heinemeier Hansson</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:world.hey.com,2005:World::Post/42931</id>
    <link href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/don-t-make-google-sell-chrome-93cefbc6"/>
    <published>2025-04-28T06:00:37Z</published>
    <summary>&lt;div class=&quot;trix-content&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;The web will be far worse off &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.msn.com/en-us/technology/tech-companies/a-judge-could-force-google-to-sell-chrome-what-you-need-to-know/ar-AA1DjlGy&quot;&gt;if Google is forced to sell Chrome&lt;/a&gt;, even if it&#39;s to atone for legitimate ad-market monopoly abuses. Which mean we&#39;ll all be worse off as the web would lose ground to actual monopoly platforms, like the iOS App Store and Google&#39;s own Play Store. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;First, Chrome won the browser war fair and square by building a better surfboard for the internet. This wasn&#39;t some opportune acquisition. This was the result of grand investments, great technical prowess, and markets doing what they&#39;re supposed to do: rewarding the best. Besides, we have a million alternatives. Firefox still exists, so does Safari,&amp;nbsp; so does the billion Chromium-based browsers like Brave and Edge. And we finally even have new engines on the way with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ladybird.org/&quot;&gt;Ladybird browser&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Look, Google&#39;s trillion-dollar business depends on a thriving web that can be searched by Google.com, that can be plastered in AdSense, and that now can feed the wisdom of AI. Thus, Google&#39;s incredible work to further the web isn&#39;t an act of charity, it&#39;s of economic self-interest, and that&#39;s why it works. Capitalism &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/quotes/68664-it-is-not-from-the-benevolence-of-the-butcher-the&quot;&gt;doesn&#39;t run on benevolence&lt;/a&gt;, but incentives.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;We want an 800-pound gorilla in the web&#39;s corner! Because Apple would love nothing better (despite the admirable work to keep up with Chrome by Team Safari) to see the web&#39;s capacity as an application platform diminished. As would every other owner of a proprietary application platform. Microsoft fought the web tooth and nail back in the 90s because they knew that a free, open application platform would undermine lock-in — and it did!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;But the vitality of that free and open application platform depends on constant development. If the web stagnates, other platforms will gain. But with Team Chrome pushing the web forward in a million ways — be it import maps, nested CSS, web push, etc. — is therefore essential.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;This is a classic wealth vs. riches mistake. Lawyers see Chrome as valuable in a moment&#39;s snapshot, but the value is all in the wealth that continued investment brings. A Chrome left to languish with half the investment will evaporate as quickly as a lottery winner&#39;s riches. Wealth requires maintenance to endure.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;Google should not get away with rigging the online ad market, but forcing it to sell Chrome will do great damage to the web.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary>
    <title>Don&#39;t make Google sell Chrome</title>
    <updated>2025-04-28T06:00:48Z</updated>
    <dc:date>2025-04-28T06:00:48Z</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>David Heinemeier Hansson</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:world.hey.com,2005:World::Post/42890</id>
    <link href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/we-ll-always-need-junior-programmers-69ddb4a1"/>
    <published>2025-04-24T07:49:03Z</published>
    <summary>&lt;div class=&quot;trix-content&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;We received over 2,200 applications for our &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/dhh/status/1909312757058482443&quot;&gt;just-closed junior programmer opening&lt;/a&gt;, and now we&#39;re going through all of them by hand and by human. No AI screening here. It&#39;s a lot of work, but we have a great team who take the work seriously, so in a few weeks, we&#39;ll be able to invite a group of finalists to the next phase.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;This highlights the folly of thinking that what it&#39;ll take to land a job like this is some specific list of criteria, though. Yes, you have to present a baseline of relevant markers to even get into consideration, like a great cover letter that doesn&#39;t smell like AI slop, promising projects or work experience or educational background, etc. But to actually get the job, you have to be the best of the ones who&#39;ve applied!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;It sounds self-evident, maybe, but I see questions time and again about it, so it must not be. Almost every job opening is grading applicants on the curve of everyone who has applied. And the best candidate of the lot gets the job. You can&#39;t quantify what that looks like in advance.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I&#39;m excited to see who makes it to the final stage. I already hear early whispers that we got some exceptional applicants in this round. It would be great to help counter the narrative that this industry no longer needs juniors. That&#39;s simply retarded.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;However good AI gets, we&#39;re always going to need people who know the ins and outs of what the machine comes up with. Maybe not as many, maybe not in the same roles, but it&#39;s truly utopian thinking that mankind won&#39;t need people capable of vetting the work done by AI in five minutes.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary>
    <title>We&#39;ll always need junior programmers</title>
    <updated>2025-04-24T07:49:03Z</updated>
    <dc:date>2025-04-24T07:49:03Z</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>David Heinemeier Hansson</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:world.hey.com,2005:World::Post/42806</id>
    <link href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/the-new-framework-13-hx370-68675e0e"/>
    <published>2025-04-17T09:49:18Z</published>
    <summary>&lt;div class=&quot;trix-content&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://frame.work/products/laptop13-diy-amd-ai300/configuration/new&quot;&gt;new AMD HX370 option&lt;/a&gt; in the Framework 13 is a good step forward in performance for developers. It runs our HEY test suite in 2m7s, compared to 2m43s for the 7840U (and 2m49s for a M4 Pro!). It&#39;s also about 20% faster in most single-core tasks than the 7840U.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;But is that enough to warrant the jump in price? AMD&#39;s latest, best chips have suddenly gotten pretty expensive. The F13 w/ HX370 now costs $1,992 with 32GB RAM / 1TB. Almost the same an M4 Pro MBP14 w/ 24GB / 1TB ($2,199). I&#39;d pick the Framework any day for its better keyboard, 3:2 matte screen, repairability, and superb Linux compatibility, but it won&#39;t be because the top option is &quot;cheaper&quot; any more.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;Of course you could also just go with the budget 6-core Ryzen AI 5 340 in same spec for $1,362. I&#39;m sure that&#39;s a great machine too. But maybe the sweet spot is actually the Ryzen AI 7 350. It &quot;only&quot; has 8 cores (vs 12 on the 370), but four of those are performance cores -- the same as the 370. And it&#39;s $300 cheaper. So ~$1,600 gets you out the door. I haven&#39;t actually tried the 350, though, so that&#39;s just speculation. I&#39;ve been running the 370 for the last few months.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Whichever chip you choose, the rest of the Framework 13 package is as good as it ever was. This remains my favorite laptop of at least the last decade. I&#39;ve been &lt;a href=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/the-year-on-linux-7f30279e&quot;&gt;running one for over a year now&lt;/a&gt;, and combined with &lt;a href=&quot;https://omakub.org/&quot;&gt;Omakub&lt;/a&gt; + &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c4OyfL5o7DU&quot;&gt;Neovim&lt;/a&gt;, it&#39;s the first machine in forever where I&#39;ve actually enjoyed programming on a 13&quot; screen. The 3:2 aspect ratio combined with Linux&#39;s superb multiple desktops that switch with 0ms lag and no animations means I barely miss the trusted 6K Apple XDR screen when working away from the desk.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The HX370 gives me about 6 hours of battery life in mixed use. About the same as the old 7840U. Though if all I&#39;m doing is writing, I can squeeze that to 8-10 hours. That&#39;s good enough for me, but not as good as a Qualcomm machine or an Apple M-chip machine. For some people, those extra hours really make the difference.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;What does make a difference, of course, is Linux. I&#39;ve written repeatedly about how much of a joy it&#39;s been to rediscover Linux on the desktop, and it&#39;s a joy that keeps on giving. For web work, it&#39;s so good. And for any work that requires even a minimum of Docker, it&#39;s so fast (as the HEY suite run time attests).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;Apple still has a strong hardware game, but their software story is falling apart. I haven&#39;t heard many people sing the praises of new iOS or macOS releases in a long while. It seems like &lt;a href=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/apple-needs-a-new-asshole-in-charge-0bf46b94&quot;&gt;without an asshole in charge&lt;/a&gt;, both have move towards more bloat, more ads, more gimmicks, more control. Linux is an incredible antidote to this nonsense these days.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;It&#39;s also just fun! Seeing &lt;a href=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/amd-in-everything-0ec0cc6e&quot;&gt;AMD catch up in outright performance&lt;/a&gt; if not efficiency has been a delight. Watching Framework perfect their 13&quot; laptop while remaining 100% backwards compatible in terms of upgrades with the first versions is heartwarming. And getting to test the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://frame.work/desktop&quot;&gt;Framework Desktop&lt;/a&gt; in advance of its Q3 release has only affirmed my commitment to both.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;But on the new HX370, it&#39;s in my opinion the best Linux laptop you can buy today, which by extension makes it the best web developer laptop too. The top spec might have gotten a bit pricey, but there are options all along the budget spectrum, which retains all the key ingredients any way. Hard to go wrong.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;Forza Framework!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary>
    <title>The new Framework 13 HX370</title>
    <updated>2025-04-17T10:03:29Z</updated>
    <dc:date>2025-04-17T10:03:29Z</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>David Heinemeier Hansson</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:world.hey.com,2005:World::Post/42666</id>
    <link href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/why-we-won-t-hire-a-junior-with-five-years-of-experience-0a548994"/>
    <published>2025-04-08T10:04:28Z</published>
    <summary>&lt;div class=&quot;trix-content&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;We just opened a &lt;a href=&quot;https://apply.workable.com/37signals/j/A97E298621/&quot;&gt;search for a new junior programmer&lt;/a&gt; at 37signals. It&#39;s been years since we last hired a junior, but the real reason the listing is turning heads is because we&#39;re open about the yearly salary: $145,849*. That&#39;s high enough that programmers with lots of experience are asking whether they could apply, even if they aren&#39;t technically &quot;junior&quot;. The answer is no.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;The reason we&#39;re willing to pay a junior more than most is because we&#39;re looking for a junior who&#39;s better than most. Not better in &quot;what do they already know&quot;, but in &quot;how far could they go&quot;. We&#39;re hiring for peak promise — and such promise only remains until it&#39;s revealed.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;Maybe it sounds a little harsh, but a programmer who&#39;s been working professionally for five years has likely already revealed their potential. What you&#39;re going to get is roughly what you see. That doesn&#39;t mean that people can&#39;t get better after that, but it means that the trajectory by which they improve has already been plotted.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;Whereas a programmer who&#39;s either straight out of school or fresh off their first internship or short-stint job is essentially all potential. So you draw their line on the basis of just a few early dots, but the line can be steep.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;It&#39;s not that different from something like the NFL scouting combine. Teams fight to find the promise of The Next All-Star. These rookies won&#39;t have the experience that someone who&#39;s already played in the league for years would have, but they have the potential to be the best. Someone who&#39;s already played for several seasons will have shown what they have and be weighed accordingly.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;This is not easy to do! Plenty of rookies, in sports and programming, may show some early potential, then fail to elevate their game to where the buyer is betting it could be. But that&#39;s the chance you take to land someone extraordinary.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;So if you know a junior programmer with less than three years of industry experience who is sparkling with potential, do let them know of our listing. And if you know someone awesome who&#39;s already a senior programmer, we also have &lt;a href=&quot;https://apply.workable.com/37signals/j/23D7D76B08/&quot;&gt;an opening for them&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;*It&#39;s a funnily precise number because it&#39;s pulled directly from the Radford salary database, which we query for the top 10% of San Francisco salaries for junior programmers.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary>
    <title>Why we won&#39;t hire a junior with five years of experience</title>
    <updated>2025-04-08T10:06:22Z</updated>
    <dc:date>2025-04-08T10:06:22Z</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>David Heinemeier Hansson</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:world.hey.com,2005:World::Post/42544</id>
    <link href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/the-year-on-linux-7f30279e"/>
    <published>2025-03-29T13:40:26Z</published>
    <summary>&lt;div class=&quot;trix-content&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;I&#39;ve been running &lt;a href=&quot;https://omakub.org&quot;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lazyvim.org/&quot;&gt;Neovim&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://frame.work/&quot;&gt;Framework&lt;/a&gt; for a year now, but it easily feels like a decade or more. That&#39;s the funny thing about habits: They can be so hard to break, but once you do, they&#39;re also easily forgotten.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;That&#39;s how it feels having left the Apple realm after two decades inside the walled garden. It was hard for the first couple of weeks, but since then, it’s rarely crossed my mind.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;Humans are rigid in the short term, but flexible in the long term. Blessed are the few who can retain the grit to push through that early mental resistance and reach new maxima.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;That is something that gets harder with age. I can feel it. It takes more of me now to wipe a mental slate clean and start over. To go back to being a beginner. But the reward for learning something new is as satisfying as ever.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;But it&#39;s also why I&#39;ve tried to be modest with the advocacy. I don&#39;t know if most developers are better off on Linux. I mean, I believe they are, at some utopian level, especially if they work for the web, using open source tooling. But I don&#39;t know if they are as humans with limited will or capacity for change.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;Of course, it&#39;s fair to say that one doesn&#39;t want to. Either because one remain a fan of Apple, in dire need of the remaining edge MacBooks retain on efficiency/battery, or simply content inside the ecosystem. There are plenty of reasons why someone might not want to change. It&#39;s not just about rigidity.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;Besides, it&#39;s a dead end trying to convince anyone of an alternative with the sharp end of a religious argument. That kind of &lt;a href=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/why-i-retired-from-the-tech-crusades-107a51ea&quot;&gt;crusading just seeds resentment and stubbornness&lt;/a&gt;. I know that all too well.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;What I&#39;ve found to work much better is planting seeds and showing off your plowshare. Let whatever curiosity that blooms find its own way towards your blue sky. The mimetic engine of persuasion runs much cleaner anyway.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;And for me, it&#39;s primarily about &lt;a href=&quot;https://omakub.org&quot;&gt;my personal computing workbench&lt;/a&gt; regardless of what the world does or doesn&#39;t. It was the same with finding Ruby. It&#39;s great when others come along for the ride, but I&#39;d also be happy taking the trip solo too.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;So consider this a postcard from a year into the Linux, Neovim, and Framework journey. The sun is still shining, the wind is in my hair, and the smile on my lips hasn&#39;t been this big since the earliest days of OS X.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary>
    <title>The Year on Linux</title>
    <updated>2025-03-29T13:58:39Z</updated>
    <dc:date>2025-03-29T13:58:39Z</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>David Heinemeier Hansson</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:world.hey.com,2005:World::Post/42534</id>
    <link href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/singularity-serenity-0198b8b5"/>
    <published>2025-03-28T12:30:59Z</published>
    <summary>&lt;div class=&quot;trix-content&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;The singularity is the point where artificial intelligence goes parabolic, surpassing humans writ large, and leads to rapid, unpredictable change. The intellectual seed of this concept was planted back in the &#39;50s by early computer pioneer John von Neumann. So it’s been here since the dawn of the modern computer, but I’ve only just come around to giving the idea consideration as something other than science fiction.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Now, this quickly becomes quasi-religious, with all the terms being as fluid as redemption, absolution, and eternity. What and when exactly is AGI (Artificial General Intelligence) or SAI (Super Artificial Intelligence)? You’ll find a million definitions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;But it really does feel like we’re on the cusp of &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;. Even the most ardent AI skeptics are probably finding it hard not to be impressed with recent advances. &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/search?q=%23Ghibli&quot;&gt;Everything Is Ghibli&lt;/a&gt; might seem like a silly gimmick, but to me, it flipped a key bit here: the style persistence, solving text in image generation, and then turning those images into &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/PJaccetturo/status/1905151190872309907&quot;&gt;incredible moving pictures&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;What makes all this progress so fascinating is that it’s clear &lt;a href=&quot;https://world.hey.com/dhh/nobody-knows-anything-9c773a5a&quot;&gt;nobody knows anything&lt;/a&gt; about what the world will look like four years from now. It’s barely been half that time since ChatGPT and Midjourney hit us in 2022, and the leaps since then have been staggering.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I’ve been playing with computers since the Commodore 64 entertained my childhood street with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kx-ZROVQGw0&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yie Ar Kung-Fu&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on its glorious 1 MHz processor. I was there when the web made the internet come alive in the mid-&#39;90s. I lined up for hours for the first iPhone to participate in the grand move to mobile. But I’ve never felt less able to predict what the next token of reality will look like.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;When you factor in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I44_zbEwz_w&quot;&gt;recent advances in robotics&lt;/a&gt; and pair those with the AI brains we’re building, it’s easy to imagine all sorts of futuristic scenarios happening very quickly: from humanoid robots finishing household chores à la &lt;em&gt;The Jetsons&lt;/em&gt; (have you seen how good it’s getting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/shorts/8vsTNFUFJEU&quot;&gt;at folding&lt;/a&gt;?) to every movie we watch being created from a novel prompt on the spot, to, yes, even armies of droids and drones fighting our wars.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;This is one of those paradigm shifts with the potential for Total Change. Like the agricultural revolution, the industrial revolution, the information revolution. The kind that rewrites society, where it was impossible to tell in advance where we’d land.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I understand why people find that uncertainty scary. But I choose to receive it as exhilarating instead. What good is it to fret about a future you don’t control anyway? That’s the marvel and the danger of progress: nobody is actually in charge! This is all being driven by a million independent agents chasing irresistible incentives. There’s no pause button, let alone an off-ramp. We’re going to be all-in whether we like it or not.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;So we might as well come to terms with that reality. Choose to marvel at the accelerating milestones we&#39;ve been hitting rather than tremble over the next.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;This is something most religions and grand philosophies have long since figured out. The world didn’t just start changing; we’ve had these lurches of forward progress before. And humans have struggled to cope with the transition since the beginning of time. So, the best intellectual frameworks have worked on ways to deal.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Christianity has the Serenity Prayer, which I’ve always been fond of:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;em&gt;God, grant me the serenity&lt;br&gt;to accept the things I cannot change,&lt;br&gt;the courage to change the things I can,&lt;br&gt;and the wisdom to know the difference.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;That’s the part most people know. But it actually continues:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;em&gt;Living one day at a time,&lt;br&gt;enjoying one moment at a time;&lt;br&gt;accepting hardship as a pathway to peace;&lt;br&gt;taking, as Jesus did,&lt;br&gt;this sinful world as it is,&lt;br&gt;not as I would have it;&lt;br&gt;trusting that You will make all things right&lt;br&gt;if I surrender to Your will;&lt;br&gt;so that I may be reasonably happy in this life&lt;br&gt;and supremely happy with You forever in the next.&lt;br&gt;Amen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;What a great frame for the mind!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Stoics were big on the same concept. Here’s Epictetus:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some things are in our control and others not. Things in our control are opinion, pursuit, desire, aversion, and, in a word, whatever are our own actions. Things not in our control are body, property, reputation, command, and, in one word, whatever are not our own actions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Buddhism does this well too. Here’s the Buddha being his wonderfully brief self:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;em&gt;Suffering does not follow one who is free from clinging.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I don’t think it’s a coincidence that all these traditions converged on the idea of letting go of what you can’t control, not clinging to any specific preferred outcome. Because you’re bound to be disappointed that way. You don’t get to know the script to life in advance, but what an incredible show, if you just let it unfold.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;This is the broader view of amor fati. You should learn to love not just your own fate, but the fate of the world — its turns, its twists, its progress, and even the inevitable regressions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The singularity may be here soon, or it may not. You’d be a fool to be convinced either way. But you’ll find serenity in accepting whatever happens.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary>
    <title>Singularity &amp; Serenity</title>
    <updated>2025-03-28T12:37:07Z</updated>
    <dc:date>2025-03-28T12:37:07Z</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <dc:date>2025-08-06T22:56:52+00:00</dc:date>
</feed>